Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
(Moon River)
(نهر القمر)
Please kill me!
من فضلك اقتلني!
Gladly.
بكل سرور.
I will kill every last one of you!
سأقتل كل واحد منكم!
The Queen Dowager has arrived!
وصلت الملكة الأرملة!
You dared to conspire against the Royal Relatives...
لقد تجرأت على التآمر ضد الأقارب الملكيين...
and bring harm to the Crown Prince.
وإلحاق الضرر بولي العهد.
- Arrest this traitor. - Harming His Royal Highness was...
- اعتقلوا هذا الخائن. - إيذاء صاحب السمو الملكي كان...
the fault of my subordinate.
خطأ مرؤوسي.
And I had proof of the affair.
وكان عندي دليل على هذه القضية.
That love letter... The Crown Prince wrote it to Park Dal.
تلك رسالة الحب... كتبها ولي العهد إلى بارك دال.
- What are you doing? Seize her now. - Arrest her immediately!
- ماذا تفعل؟ اقبض عليها الآن. - اعتقلها فورًا!
- Yes, Your Majesty. - Yes, Your Majesty.
- نعم يا جلالة الملك. - نعم يا جلالة الملك.
I have been wronged.
لقد تعرضت للظلم.
Your Majesty, I have been wronged!
يا صاحب الجلالة، لقد ظلموني!
Your Majesty, I have been wronged.
يا صاحب الجلالة، لقد ظلموني.
The letter you brought as proof of an affair...
الرسالة التي أحضرتها كدليل على وجود علاقة غرامية...
was confirmed that it was written by His Highness, the Crown Prince.
وتم التأكد من أنها من تأليف صاحب السمو ولي العهد.
So what brings you here now?
إذن ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا الآن؟
There is no place in this place for you, Grand Prince Je Un.
لا يوجد مكان لك في هذا المكان، أيها الأمير العظيم جي أون.
Therefore, you must leave.
لذلك يجب عليك الرحيل.
Did you not know? I already live outside the palace.
ألم تعلم؟ أنا أعيش خارج القصر بالفعل.
Then, I shall return to my home.
ثم سأعود إلى منزلي.
Left State Councillor. Please give me one more chance.
أيها المستشار اليساري، أرجوك أعطني فرصة أخرى.
I will not fail you this time!
لن أخذلك هذه المرة!
- My lord! - Careless words...
- سيدي! - كلمات غير مدروسة...
can bring great harm.
يمكن أن يسبب ضررًا كبيرًا.
(Chapter Eight: Silence is Golden)
(الفصل الثامن: الصمت من ذهب)
Your Royal Highness, let a court lady do that.
صاحب السمو الملكي، دع سيدة من البلاط تفعل ذلك.
I will do it myself.
سأفعل ذلك بنفسي.
I will do it.
أنا سأفعلها.
And what should I do with Court Lady Park's things?
وماذا يجب أن أفعل بأشياء السيدة بارك؟
Get rid of them.
تخلص منهم
- She will not need them anymore. - What do you mean?
- لن تحتاج إليهم بعد الآن. - ماذا تقصد؟
Then should I get rid of this scent pouch too?
إذن هل يجب علي أن أتخلص من كيس العطر هذا أيضًا؟
Leave that.
اترك ذلك.
It is evidence that the man behind the Choraengi Mask dropped.
إنه دليل على أن الرجل الذي كان وراء قناع تشوراينجي سقط.
But this scent pouch...
ولكن هذه الحقيبة العطرية...
Last year,
في العام الماضي،
His Majesty gave these to palace staff...
أعطى جلالته هذه الهدايا لموظفي القصر...
to celebrate Queen Dowager's birthday.
للاحتفال بعيد ميلاد الملكة الأرملة.
How could the man behind the Choraengi Mask have one?
كيف يمكن للرجل الذي يقف خلف قناع تشوراينجي أن يمتلك قناعًا؟
What? Palace staff?
ماذا؟ موظفو القصر؟
This is the entry and exit log...
هذا هو سجل الدخول والخروج...
of the palace staff's from the last six months.
من موظفي القصر خلال الأشهر الستة الماضية.
But why did you have me bring this?
ولكن لماذا طلبت مني أن أحضر هذا؟
We could have just inspected all of the staff's scent pouches.
كان بإمكاننا أن نقوم بفحص جميع أكياس العطور الخاصة بالموظفين.
This scent pouch is his?
هل هذه الحقيبة العطرية له؟
Scent pouches are typically used by women.
تُستخدم الأكياس العطرية عادةً من قبل النساء.
The Choraengi Mask?
قناع تشوراينجي؟
A sack?
كيس؟
Five.
خمسة.
One.
واحد.
Once every five days.
مرة كل خمسة أيام.
You traded poisonous insects with the Choraengi Mask.
لقد قمت بتبادل الحشرات السامة باستخدام قناع تشورينجي.
Is that correct?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Find a court lady...
العثور على سيدة المحكمة...
who left between 9pm and 1am every 5 days.
الذين غادروا بين الساعة 9 مساءً و 1 صباحًا كل 5 أيام.
This...
هذا...
You want me to search through all of this?
هل تريد مني أن أبحث في كل هذا؟
This is tyranny and an abuse of power.
هذا هو الاستبداد واستغلال السلطة.
It is not an abuse of power when the Crown Prince does it.
ليس إساءة لاستخدام السلطة عندما يقوم ولي العهد بذلك.
Besides,
بجانب،
you would rather be looking through this log...
كنت تفضل أن تنظر من خلال هذا السجل...
than at your name in the death book, would you not?
من أن يكون اسمك في كتاب الموت، أليس كذلك؟
(Jo Myeong Im)
(جو ميونغ إيم)
Over the past 3 months, once every 5 days,
على مدى الأشهر الثلاثة الماضية، مرة كل 5 أيام،
only one person left regularly at 9pm or 1am.
شخص واحد فقط يغادر بانتظام في الساعة 9 مساءً أو 1 صباحًا.
Where is the Chief Court Lady now?
أين سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية الآن؟
This was found in the Chief Court Lady's quarters.
تم العثور على هذا في مقر سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية.
So the Chief Court Lady really was the Choraengi Mask.
لذا فإن سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية كانت في الحقيقة هي قناع تشوراينجي.
The Left State Councillor's blade...
شفرة المستشار اليساري للدولة...
knows no hesitation.
لا يعرف التردد.
Tell the Police Bureau to watch the snake catchers.
اطلب من مكتب الشرطة مراقبة صائدي الثعابين.
He will need to procure food for the Jimjo,
سوف يحتاج إلى توفير الطعام لجيمجو،
so he will be looking for new catchers.
لذلك سوف يبحث عن صيادين جدد.
If we move on them without reason,
إذا تحركنا عليهم بدون سبب،
the Left State Councillor will not approve.
لن يوافق المستشار اليساري للدولة.
Yes, that is too rash. If you could please reconsider...
نعم، هذا متهور جدًا. لو سمحتَ بإعادة النظر...
There is...
هنالك...
There is no time.
ليس هناك وقت.
I must end this before the Left State Councillor harms Dal.
يجب أن أنهي هذا الأمر قبل أن يؤذي مستشار الدولة اليساري دال.
I have to do something!
يجب علي أن أفعل شيئا!
It is mine.
إنها لي.
This...
هذا...
I received this before I entered the palace.
لقد تلقيت هذا قبل دخولي القصر.
This one thing...
هذا الشيء الواحد...
is mine.
هي ملكي.
Dal.
من.
Dal, are you all right? Dal.
دال، هل أنت بخير؟ دال.
Dal, are you all right?
دال، هل أنت بخير؟
This will not do. I will go get the Royal Physician.
هذا لن ينفع. سأذهب لأستدعي الطبيب الملكي.
Why am I here?
لماذا انا هنا؟
Have we not switched back?
هل لم نعود إلى الوراء؟
Here, calm down and look. It is my face.
اهدأ وانظر، إنه وجهي.
But...
لكن...
how did we switch back then?
كيف تحولنا حينها؟
I am not sure either.
أنا لست متأكدة أيضًا.
When I came to after being whipped, we had already switched back.
عندما استعدت وعيي بعد أن تعرضت للجلد، كنا قد عدنا بالفعل إلى الوضع السابق.
When we switched bodies before, we were not whipped.
عندما قمنا بتبديل الأجساد من قبل، لم نتعرض للضرب.
Still, it is a relief...
ومع ذلك، فهو أمر مريح...
that we have switched back.
أننا عدنا إلى الوراء.
How can you be smiling right now?
كيف يمكنك أن تبتسم الآن؟
What do you want me to do?
ماذا تريدني أن أفعل؟
- I had to save you. - Who asked you to save me?
- كان عليّ أن أنقذك. - من طلب منك أن تنقذني؟
Since I got tangled up with you, I have not had a moment's peace.
منذ أن انخرطت معك، لم أشعر بلحظة سلام واحدة.
And do you have any idea how many times I nearly died?
وهل لديك أي فكرة عن عدد المرات التي كدت أموت فيها؟
I cannot stand to see you like this by my side.
لا أستطيع أن أتحمل رؤيتك بجانبي بهذا الشكل.
In any case,
على أي حال،
we agreed I would leave once we switched back.
لقد اتفقنا على أنني سأغادر بمجرد عودتنا.
Who said you could leave?
من قال لك أنك تستطيع المغادرة؟
I am going to make you my concubine.
سأجعلك محظيتي.
I have to keep you in my sight.
يجب علي أن أبقيك في نظري.
I need to keep you close so I know you are safe.
أحتاج إلى إبقاءك قريبًا حتى أعرف أنك بأمان.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
I will be your shield,
سأكون درعك
and you will hide behind me.
وسوف تختبئ خلفي.
Until that shield is broken.
حتى يتم كسر هذا الدرع.
I told you to stay at my chambers. Why did you insist on coming here?
طلبتُ منك البقاء في غرفتي. لماذا أصررتَ على المجيء إلى هنا؟
You were just dying for your silk bed, were you not?
لقد كنت تموت من أجل سريرك الحريري، أليس كذلك؟
Now that you have switched back, you can enjoy it all you want.
الآن بعد أن قمت بالتبديل مرة أخرى، يمكنك الاستمتاع به كما تريد.
As if there is only one silk bed in this whole palace.
وكأن هناك سرير حرير واحد فقط في هذا القصر بأكمله.
Here. I hope this eases your pain, even just a little.
أتمنى أن يخفف هذا من ألمك، ولو قليلاً.
You are in no condition to be up. Lie down. I will leave you to rest.
أنت لستَ في حالةٍ تسمح لكَ بالاستيقاظ. استلقِ. سأتركك ترتاح.
Actually...
في الحقيقة...
Yes? What is it?
نعم؟ ما هو؟
- Is there something you need? - No, that is not it.
- هل هناك شيء تحتاجه؟ - لا، ليس هذا هو.
It is just something I was wondering.
إنه مجرد شيء كنت أتساءل عنه.
It is about...
إن الأمر يتعلق ب...
that Four Frames of Life painting.
تلك اللوحة التي تصور أربعة إطارات من الحياة.
What?
ماذا؟
Why did you put it in that love letter?
لماذا وضعتها في تلك الرسالة الغرامية؟
You know,
أنت تعرف،
the one that goes, "The night is dark, and the moon is bright."
الذي يقول "الليل مظلم والقمر منير"
Or whatever. That one.
أو أيا كان. هذا.
In a letter so cheesy,
في رسالة مبتذلة جدًا،
why did you tuck in a drawing...
لماذا قمت بوضع رسم في...
of the two of us?
من بيننا الاثنين؟
That is...
إنه...
The thing is...
الشئ هو...
The Left State Councillor will make bolder attempts to harm Dal.
سيبذل المستشار اليساري للدولة محاولات أكثر جرأة لإلحاق الضرر بداللة.
Instead of a hasty confession,
بدلا من الاعتراف المتسرع،
taking down the Left State Councillor must come first.
إن إسقاط مستشار الدولة اليساري يجب أن يأتي في المقام الأول.
There was nowhere else to put it.
لم يكن هناك مكان آخر لوضعه.
Then I guess...
ثم أعتقد...
you are making me a Royal Concubine...
أنت تجعلني محظية ملكية...
because there is nowhere else for me.
لأنه لا يوجد مكان آخر بالنسبة لي.
You must stay by my side until I find evidence...
يجب عليك البقاء بجانبي حتى أجد الدليل...
and take down the Left State Councillor.
وإسقاط مستشار الدولة اليساري.
You were hurt because of me,
لقد تأذيت بسببي
so I have to take responsibility.
لذلك يجب أن أتحمل المسؤولية.
What am I, bruised fruit?
ما أنا، الفاكهة المكسورة؟
Or a cracked pot?
أو وعاء متصدع؟
And what is all this about making me a concubine because I got hurt?
وما كل هذا الذي يجعلني محظية لأنني تعرضت للأذى؟
And what about "until I take down the Left State Councillor" part?
وماذا عن الجزء "حتى أسقط مستشار الدولة اليساري"؟
Once you are done with him, will you just toss me aside too?
بمجرد الانتهاء منه، هل ستتخلص مني أيضًا؟
And I thought maybe his heart...
وفكرت ربما أن قلبه...
was for me, not the Crown Princess.
كان بالنسبة لي، وليس لولي العهد.
Talk about counting my chickens before they hatched.
تحدث عن عد الدجاج قبل أن يفقس.
It really stings.
إنه مؤلم حقا.
Goodness.
الخير.
Why on earth am I hurting inside and out?
لماذا على الأرض أنا أعاني من الداخل والخارج؟
This is just miserable.
هذا أمر بائس حقًا.
A Royal Concubine?
محظية ملكية؟
Do you think the Left State Councillor will just sit by...
هل تعتقد أن المستشار اليساري للدولة سوف يجلس مكتوف الأيدي؟
if you bring in a concubine before the Royal Wedding?
إذا أحضرت محظية قبل الزفاف الملكي؟
I am no longer afraid of the Left State Councillor.
لم أعد خائفا من المستشار اليساري للدولة.
He would kill his own people without a second thought.
كان سيقتل شعبه دون تفكير ثانٍ.
I must protect Dal.
يجب علي أن أحمي دال.
This time, I swear...
هذه المرة أقسم...
I will protect her at all costs.
سأحميها بكل ثمن.
Please help me.
من فضلك ساعدني.
Father.
أب.
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
What parent can ever win against their child?
ما هو الوالد الذي يمكنه الفوز على طفله؟
I hereby appoint Park Dal...
أنا أعين بموجب هذا بارك دال ...
as Crown Prince's Concubine of the Junior Fifth Rank.
كمحظية ولي العهد من الدرجة الخامسة الصغرى.
From this day forward, this girl will be attending to you.
من هذا اليوم فصاعدا، هذه الفتاة سوف تعتني بك.
I am Yeon Sim of the Hong clan. I will serve you devotedly.
أنا يون سيم من عشيرة هونغ. سأخدمك بإخلاص.
Thank you. I'm counting on you too.
شكرا لك. أنا أعتمد عليك أيضًا.
You must address her informally. To do otherwise is against protocol.
يجب عليك مخاطبتها بشكل غير رسمي. خلاف ذلك مخالف للبروتوكول.
But we have only just met.
لكننا التقينا للتو.
How can you say that when I brought your former roommate?
كيف يمكنك أن تقول ذلك عندما أحضرت زميلك السابق في السكن؟
I see.
أرى.
Right, right.
يمينًا، يمينًا.
But...
لكن...
why are you suddenly speaking with an accent?
لماذا تتحدث بلكنة فجأة؟
It is just...
إنه فقط...
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
Well,
حسنًا،
did you sleep well?
هل نمت جيدا؟
Yes.
نعم.
I did.
فعلتُ.
You have...
لديك...
put your hair up.
ارفع شعرك.
Oh, my hair...
أوه شعري...
Yes.
نعم.
Does it look strange?
هل يبدو غريبا؟
No, it is just...
لا، إنه فقط...
It looks good on you.
إنه يبدو جيدا عليك.
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
- What is it? - Hurry.
- ما هو؟ - اسرع.
What is all the fuss about? What is it?
ما كل هذه الضجة؟ ما الأمر؟
- Your Royal Highness. - What has happened here?
- صاحب السمو الملكي. - ماذا حدث هنا؟
Poisonous insects were found in the jar, Your Highness.
لقد تم العثور على حشرات سامة في الجرة يا صاحب السمو.
They are from the medicinal food merchants,
وهم من تجار الأغذية الطبية،
so perhaps there was a mix-up.
ربما كان هناك خلط.
I will launch an investigation at once.
سأبدأ التحقيق على الفور.
Cheonghye Merchant Guild?
نقابة التجار تشونغهي؟
Who manages the deliveries from the merchant guilds?
من يدير عمليات التسليم من النقابات التجارية؟
The previous Chief Court Lady was in charge of it.
وكانت رئيسة المحكمة السابقة مسؤولة عن ذلك.
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
If its food has appeared, then the creature must be here too.
إذا ظهر طعامه، فلا بد أن يكون المخلوق هنا أيضًا.
Do you have any idea where it could be?
هل لديك أي فكرة أين يمكن أن يكون؟
A place known only to the Chief Court Lady.
مكان معروف فقط للسيدة رئيسة المحكمة.
Somewhere dark and damp within the palace.
في مكان مظلم ورطب داخل القصر.
No way. This tiny little thing is the Jimjo?
مستحيل. هذا الشيء الصغير هو جيمجو؟
It is a fledgling.
إنه فرخ.
- We have to find the mother. - Now we have found its young,
- علينا أن نجد الأم. - الآن وجدنا صغارها،
will this not be enough to implicate the Left State Councillor?
هل لن يكون هذا كافيا لتوريط مستشار الدولة اليساري؟
The log, the feather from her room, and now this secret cell.
السجل، والريشة من غرفتها، والآن هذه الزنزانة السرية.
It all fits a little too perfectly that she is the owner of the Jimjo.
كل هذا يناسبها تمامًا لأنها مالكة Jimjo.
That is true.
هذا صحيح.
There is no evidence linking her to the Left State Councillor.
لا يوجد دليل يربطها بالمستشار اليساري للدولة.
This Jimjo chick...
هذه الفتاة جيمجو...
is a taunt and a warning from the Left State Councillor.
إنها استهزاء وتحذير من مستشار الدولة اليساري.
So he planned to use her as a scapegoat from the beginning.
لذلك خطط لاستخدامها ككبش فداء منذ البداية.
What is more,
وما هو أكثر من ذلك،
it is a warning to stop digging into the Gyesa Year Incident.
إنه تحذير للتوقف عن البحث في حادثة عام جيسا.
As you commanded, I have made sure all the evidence...
كما أمرت، لقد تأكدت من جميع الأدلة...
points to the Chief Court Lady as the owner.
يشير إلى سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية باعتبارها المالك.
The entry log, the feather in her quarters,
سجل الدخول، الريشة في غرفتها،
and the Jimjo's food have all been planted.
وقد تم زراعة كل طعام الجيمجو.
By now,
بحلول الآن،
our dear Crown Prince must be quite confused.
لا بد أن ولي عهدنا العزيز في حيرة شديدة.
But is it really okay for the Crown Prince to have found the Jimjo?
لكن هل من المقبول حقًا أن يجد ولي العهد الجيمجو؟
Since the Jimjo was found inside the palace,
منذ أن تم العثور على جيمجو داخل القصر،
he will not be so quick to reveal its existence.
لن يكون سريعًا في الكشف عن وجوده.
More importantly,
والأهم من ذلك،
I ordered you to kill everyone involved with my Jimjo.
لقد أمرتك بقتل كل من له علاقة بجيمجو.
How does the Crown Prince know about you?
كيف يعرف ولي العهد عنك؟
Why is he checking snake catchers?
لماذا يقوم بفحص صائدي الثعابين؟
Did a dead man start talking? Is that it?
هل بدأ رجل ميت بالتحدث؟ هل هذا كل شيء؟
Is someone I had killed still alive? Is that what happened?
هل ما زال الشخص الذي قتلته حيًا؟ هل هذا ما حدث؟
Please kill me.
من فضلك اقتلني.
Do not disappoint me again.
لا تخيب ظني مرة أخرى.
Your mother deserves to be free, does she not?
والدتك تستحق أن تكون حرة، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, Your Excellency.
نعم يا صاحب السعادة.
A Jimjo chick was found inside the palace.
تم العثور على فرخ جيمجو داخل القصر.
Do you know a way to use the chick to find its mother?
هل تعرف طريقة استخدام الفرخ للعثور على أمه؟
How could a Jimjo chick have come from the palace?
كيف يمكن لفرخ جيمجو أن يأتي من القصر؟
- Why are you looking at me? - Only you speak Qing, Highness.
- لماذا تنظر إلي؟ - أنت فقط تتحدث تشينغ، صاحب السمو.
What makes you think I can speak their language?
ما الذي يجعلك تعتقد أنني أستطيع التحدث بلغتهم؟
Gang. You understand the Qing language?
يا جماعة، هل تفهمون لغة تشينغ؟
Well...
حسنًا...
I picked some up here and there.
التقطت بعضًا منها هنا وهناك.
Hey, last time we met, I noticed you can speak Joseon,
مرحبًا، في آخر مرة التقينا فيها، لاحظت أنك تستطيع التحدث بلغة جوسون،
so just speak in Joseon.
لذا تحدث فقط باللغة جوسون.
Why must I yield to you as the Crown Prince? I have my pride.
لماذا عليّ أن أستسلم لك كولي للعهد؟ لديّ كبريائي.
Your Royal Highness, he might change his mind anytime.
صاحب السمو الملكي، قد يغير رأيه في أي وقت.
You should set aside your pride for now...
ينبغي عليك أن تضع كبريائك جانبًا في الوقت الحالي...
and get the information we need first.
والحصول على المعلومات التي نحتاجها أولاً.
- No, I mean... - The chick...
- لا، أعني... - الفتاة...
- The chick? - It cannot kill people.
- الفرخ؟ - لا يمكنه قتل الناس.
That is why its mother protects it.
ولهذا السبب تحميه أمه.
I see.
أرى.
Its venom is weak, so the mother protects it.
سمها ضعيف، لذلك تحميها الأم.
Is he talking about maternal instinct?
هل يتحدث عن غريزة الأمومة؟
A long time ago, a chick was sold far away.
منذ زمن بعيد، تم بيع فرخ في مكان بعيد.
Its mother found it and brought it back home.
لقد وجدته أمه وأعادته إلى المنزل.
Home? You mean...
المنزل؟ هل تقصد...
It would return to the place it was confined?
هل سيعود إلى المكان الذي كان محصورا فيه؟
A homing instinct?
غريزة العودة إلى الوطن؟
You said it was sold far away. How far exactly?
قلتَ إنه بِيعَ بعيدًا. كم المسافة بالضبط؟
The next village over.
القرية التالية.
About 8km.
حوالي 8 كم.
About 8km?
حوالي 8 كم؟
What is it, Your Highness?
ما الأمر يا صاحب السمو؟
For the mother to fetch its chick from 8km away,
لكي تتمكن الأم من إحضار فرخها من مسافة 8 كم،
it must have heard the chick's cries and come for it.
لا بد أنه سمع صراخ الفرخ وجاء إليه.
Which means...
وهذا يعني...
the chick should be able to hear its mother's cries too.
يجب أن يكون الفرخ قادرًا على سماع صراخ أمه أيضًا.
For now, our best bet is to use the chick to find its mother.
في الوقت الحالي، أفضل رهان لدينا هو استخدام الفرخ للعثور على أمه.
Since adult Jimjo birds are large and usually kept in mountain caves,
نظرًا لأن طيور جيمجو البالغة كبيرة الحجم ويتم الاحتفاظ بها عادةً في كهوف الجبال،
we will search the nearby mountains...
سوف نبحث في الجبال القريبة...
Wait a moment.
انتظر لحظة.
I need to speak with her.
أريد أن أتحدث معها.
You promised to send Dal away when your bodies switched.
لقد وعدت بإرسال دال بعيدًا عندما تتبدل أجسادكم.
But now she is a Royal Concubine?
ولكن الآن أصبحت محظية ملكية؟
Did I not tell you? I told you you could not protect Dal!
ألم أخبرك؟ قلت لك أنك لا تستطيع حماية دال!
Something has felt off all along.
لقد شعرت أن هناك شيئًا غريبًا طوال الوقت.
The fact that you planned to flee to Qing when I, the Crown Prince,
حقيقة أنك خططت للهروب إلى تشينغ عندما كنت أنا ولي العهد،
promised I would protect Dal.
لقد وعدت بأن أحمي دال.
You believed that absurd tale about our bodies switching.
لقد صدقت تلك الحكاية السخيفة حول تحول أجسادنا.
And now,
والآن،
your desperate attempts to keep me and Dal apart.
محاولاتك اليائسة لإبقائي أنا ودال منفصلين.
Just like with the Crown Princess five years ago,
تمامًا كما حدث مع ولي العهد قبل خمس سنوات،
do you want to lose Dal to the Left State Councillor as well?
هل تريد أن تخسر دال أمام مستشار الدولة اليساري أيضًا؟
I am begging you, let Dal go.
أنا أتوسل إليك، دع دال يذهب.
Dal...
من...
said she is tired of living on the run.
قالت إنها سئمت من العيش هاربة.
And I will protect her this time, no matter what.
وسوف أحميها هذه المرة مهما كان الأمر.
Both Dal and her dreams.
دال وأحلامها.
A Crown Prince's concubine?
محظية ولي العهد؟
With the Royal Wedding just days away,
مع اقتراب حفل الزفاف الملكي بعد أيام قليلة،
he is taking a concubine?
هل هو يأخذ محظية؟
He defies you, Left State Councillor!
إنه يتحداك يا مستشار الدولة اليساري!
How can you be so calm? What if she bears him a son?
كيف تكونين هادئةً هكذا؟ ماذا لو أنجبت له ولدًا؟
Is there anyone more troublesome...
هل هناك أي شخص أكثر إزعاجا...
than the firstborn son of a Royal Concubine?
من الابن البكر للمحظية الملكية؟
Just wait and see.
فقط انتظر وشاهد.
After all, there is no stronger leash than a weakness.
في نهاية المطاف، لا يوجد قيد أقوى من الضعف.
- Your Highness! Left State... - Unbelievable.
- صاحب السمو! الولاية اليسرى... - لا يُصدَّق.
He has tossed propriety to the dogs, has he not?
لقد ألقى باللياقة للكلاب، أليس كذلك؟
Your Royal Highness, this is not about propriety now.
صاحب السمو الملكي، الأمر لا يتعلق باللياقة الآن.
It is the Left State Councillor.
إنه مستشار الدولة اليساري.
With Concubine Park... He is...
مع محظية بارك... هو...
We meet again, Lady Park.
لقد التقينا مرة أخرى، ليدي بارك.
Left State Councillor. What brings you all the way here?
أيها المستشار اليساري، ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
I came to apologise for my rudeness during the recent interrogation...
جئت للاعتذار عن وقاحتي أثناء الاستجواب الأخير...
and to congratulate you on becoming a Royal Concubine.
وأهنئك على أن تصبحي محظية ملكية.
And for a few other reasons.
ولأسباب أخرى قليلة.
- I also had something to confirm. - Confirm what?
- كان لدي أيضًا شيئًا لأؤكده. - تأكيد ماذا؟
That is all right.
هذا جيد.
I have already confirmed what I needed to.
لقد أكدت بالفعل ما أحتاج إليه.
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
What brings you here all of a sudden?
ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا فجأة؟
To what do we owe the honour, Your Royal Highness?
بماذا ندين بهذا الشرف، يا صاحب السمو الملكي؟
A state councillor meeting the Royal Concubine alone...
عضو مجلس الدولة يلتقي المحظية الملكية بمفرده...
in broad daylight...
في وضح النهار...
I was worried it might cause talk, so I came.
كنت قلقة من أن ذلك قد يسبب الحديث، لذلك جئت.
I am moved by Your Royal Highness's concern for me,
لقد تأثرت باهتمام سموكم بي،
I could weep.
أستطيع البكاء.
Lady Park, you may leave us.
ليدي بارك، يمكنك أن تتركينا.
Pardon?
عفو؟
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموك.
Then I, too, shall take my leave.
ثم سأغادر أنا أيضًا.
But, Your Royal Highness.
ولكن، صاحب السمو الملكي.
Why take on another weakness with that soft heart of yours?
لماذا تتحمل ضعفًا آخر بهذا القلب الرقيق؟
What do you...
ما يفعله لك...
A person's greatest weakness is love.
أعظم نقاط ضعف الإنسان هو الحب.
Did I not tell you so?
ألم أخبرك بذلك؟
I shall take my leave.
سوف آخذ إجازتي.
I lost the Crown Princess, and with her, my laughter and love.
لقد فقدت ولي العهد، ومعها ضحكتي وحبي.
This concubine appointment is a matter of responsibility.
إن تعيين هذه المحظية هو مسألة مسؤولية.
As you know, Lady Park saved my life at Sinjusa.
كما تعلمون، لقد أنقذت السيدة بارك حياتي في سينجوسا.
She is the one who saved my life and was harmed because of me.
إنها هي التي أنقذت حياتي وتضررت بسببي.
How could I possibly turn my back on her?
كيف يمكنني أن أدير ظهري لها؟
It seems you thought you found a way to protect her from me,
يبدو أنك ظننت أنك وجدت طريقة لحمايتها مني،
but instead, you have only been exposed.
لكن بدلاً من ذلك، تم كشفك فقط.
I am talking about your affection, which you concealed with this lie.
أنا أتحدث عن عاطفتك التي أخفيتها بهذه الكذبة.
What were you thinking, going to him because he summoned you?
ماذا كنت تفكر عندما ذهبت إليه لأنه استدعاك؟
Have you already forgotten why you became a concubine?
هل نسيت بالفعل لماذا أصبحت محظية؟
How could I forget? You remind me every chance you get.
كيف أنسى؟ تُذكرني كلما سنحت لك الفرصة.
Fine.
بخير.
I will just hole up in this pavilion so I do not get in your way.
سأختبئ في هذا الجناح حتى لا أقف في طريقك.
Just bear with it for a little longer.
فقط تحمل الأمر لفترة أطول قليلاً.
I am slowly making progress.
أنا أحرز تقدما ببطء.
You just met with the boy from Qing, did you not?
لقد التقيت للتو بالصبي من تشينغ، أليس كذلك؟
What did he say? Is he still refusing to talk?
ماذا قال؟ هل لا يزال يرفض الكلام؟
It seems the chick and its mother communicate over long distances.
يبدو أن الفرخ وأمه يتواصلان عبر مسافات طويلة.
Since the birds are originally from the high mountains,
وبما أن الطيور أصلها من الجبال العالية،
it is a plausible theory. The hunters died within three days.
إنها نظرية معقولة. مات الصيادون في غضون ثلاثة أيام.
The bird must be within a three-day round trip from the capital.
يجب أن يكون الطائر على مسافة ثلاثة أيام ذهابًا وإيابًا من العاصمة.
Then it is highly likely it is inside the capital.
ومن ثم فمن المرجح جدًا أن يكون داخل العاصمة.
He hid it for five years,
لقد أخفاها لمدة خمس سنوات،
so it is somewhere tied to the Left State Councillor.
لذا فهو مرتبط في مكان ما بمستشار الدولة اليساري.
I will narrow down the locations and use the chick to find its mother.
سأقوم بتضييق المواقع واستخدام الفرخ للعثور على والدته.
Once I capture the Jimjo alive...
بمجرد أن أتمكن من القبض على جيمجو حيًا...
and prove its habitat is linked to the Left State Councillor,
وإثبات أن موطنه مرتبط بمستشار الدولة اليساري،
he will be finished for treason.
سيتم القضاء عليه بتهمة الخيانة.
- Great. What should I do? - Nothing!
- رائع. ماذا أفعل؟ - لا شيء!
Now that I have my body back, this revenge is mine and mine alone.
الآن بعد أن استعدت جسدي، هذا الانتقام هو ملكي وحدي.
Forget half. You are not even getting a sliver.
انسَ النصف. لن تحصل حتى على شظية.
So, from now on, stay out of the Gyesa Year Incident.
لذا، من الآن فصاعدًا، ابق بعيدًا عن حادثة عام جيسا.
If you were not going to let me in on it,
إذا لم تسمح لي بالدخول في هذا الأمر،
then why did you explain the plan in such detail?
إذن لماذا شرحت الخطة بهذه التفاصيل؟
It was not a plan. It was an explanation.
لم تكن خطة، بل كان تفسيرًا.
That I will finish my revenge myself without your help...
أنني سأكمل انتقامي بنفسي دون مساعدتك...
and take down the Left State Councillor.
وإسقاط مستشار الدولة اليساري.
Because I...
لأني...
have staked my life on this revenge.
لقد راهنت بحياتي على هذا الانتقام.
If you give your life for someone who is already dead,
إذا أعطيت حياتك لشخص ميت بالفعل،
you will just end up with two dead people.
سوف ينتهي بك الأمر فقط مع شخصين ميتين.
The living are meant to live.
إن الأحياء خلقوا ليعيشوا.
Idiot.
غبي.
The Crown Prince's Concubine will be the Deposed Crown Princess.
ستكون محظية ولي العهد هي ولي العهد المخلوع.
But many have already seen her body. How can we...
لكن كثيرين رأوا جثتها. كيف لنا...
What they saw was a corpse, decayed beyond recognition.
ما رأوه كان جثة متحللة لدرجة لا يمكن التعرف عليها.
Public opinion is more powerful than evidence.
الرأي العام أقوى من الأدلة.
People lose their lives over false accusations of adultery,
يفقد الناس حياتهم بسبب اتهامات كاذبة بالزنا،
and a poisoning can be twisted into a curse.
ويمكن أن يتحول التسمم إلى لعنة.
So why would they not believe someone dead is now alive?
فلماذا لا يصدقون أن شخصًا ميتًا أصبح الآن حيًا؟
I will reach the concubine's neighbours in Boryeong.
سأصل إلى جيران المحظية في بوريونج.
Here are the mountains within three days of the capital.
وهنا الجبال على بعد ثلاثة أيام من العاصمة.
They must have hidden it somewhere difficult to find.
لا بد أنهم أخفوه في مكان يصعب العثور عليه.
- The chick can lead us to its mom. - Yes.
- يستطيع الفرخ أن يقودنا إلى أمه. - نعم.
Still, we have come a long way.
ومع ذلك، فقد قطعنا شوطا طويلا.
When you think about it, it is thanks to Prince Je Un's book.
عندما تفكر في الأمر، فإن الفضل في ذلك يعود إلى كتاب الأمير جي أون.
My apologies, Your Highness.
اعتذاري، صاحب السمو.
Do not be.
لا تكن.
It is not like you are wrong.
ليس الأمر وكأنك مخطئ.
I am glad you know Choraengi Mask is the Chief Court Lady.
يسعدني أنك تعرف أن قناع تشورينجي هي سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية.
I have felt awful this whole time that I could not be of any help.
لقد شعرت بالرعب طوال هذا الوقت لأنني لم أتمكن من تقديم أي مساعدة.
Why are you not calling me out?
لماذا لا تتصل بي؟
You should ask why I took everything and then ignored our promise.
يجب عليك أن تسأل لماذا أخذت كل شيء ثم تجاهلت وعدنا.
You should be yelling at me, calling me a coward and a jerk.
كان ينبغي عليك أن تصرخ في وجهي، وتسميني جبانًا وغبيًا.
Your silence makes me want to fight with you for no reason.
صمتك يجعلني أرغب في القتال معك بدون سبب.
What are you talking about?
ماذا تتحدث عنه؟
The Choraengi Mask's identity and that the Jimjo is alive...
هوية قناع تشوراينجي وأن جيمجو على قيد الحياة...
I discovered all of that thanks to the book you wrote.
لقد اكتشفت كل ذلك بفضل الكتاب الذي كتبته.
I got something out of it too, so we are even for you deceiving me.
لقد حصلت على شيء منه أيضًا، لذلك نحن حتى بالنسبة لك تخدعني.
And since we made a promise,
ومنذ أن قطعنا وعدًا،
I will guarantee the Crown Princess Consort's safety.
سأضمن سلامة ولي العهد الأميرة.
- Thank you, Gang! - Get off me. That is disgusting.
- شكرًا لكم يا جماعة! - انصرفوا عني. هذا مقرف.
This is what brothers do.
هذا ما يفعله الإخوة.
By the way, what is going on?
بالمناسبة، ماذا يحدث؟
What is this about Dal becoming the Crown Prince's Concubine?
ما الأمر بشأن أن دال أصبحت محظية ولي العهد؟
I am doing it to protect her.
انا أفعل ذلك لحمايتها.
I will prove that the Left State Councillor...
سأثبت أن مستشار الدولة اليساري...
is the master of the Jimjo.
هو سيد الجيمجو.
When I do, you take the Crown Princess Consort... No.
عندما أفعل ذلك، تأخذ زوجة ولي العهد... لا.
Take your woman's hand and run away.
خذ يد امرأتك واهرب.
Protect your love.
حماية حبك.
When I said you were horrible, I lied.
عندما قلت أنك فظيع، كذبت.
And when I said I was over you,
وعندما قلت أنني تجاوزتك،
that was a lie.
لقد كانت كذبة.
- Why all of a sudden? - Left State Councillor will fall.
- لماذا فجأة؟ - سوف يسقط المستشار اليساري للدولة.
And you will be dragged down with him.
وسوف تسحب معه إلى الأسفل.
- My father will not fall. - He will.
- لن يسقط والدي. - سوف يسقط.
When he does, I will take your hand and we will run away together.
عندما يفعل ذلك، سأمسك بيدك ونهرب معًا.
That day will never come.
هذا اليوم لن يأتي أبدا .
It will. It most certainly will.
سوف يحدث ذلك. بالتأكيد سوف يحدث ذلك.
We will be happy. We must be. So please,
سنكون سعداء. يجب أن نكون كذلك. لذا من فضلكم،
trust me and just wait a little longer.
ثق بي وانتظر فقط لفترة أطول قليلاً.
Consummate our marriage?
إتمام زواجنا؟
Why are they suddenly washing me?
لماذا يغسلونني فجأة؟
Do I smell or something?
هل أشم رائحة أو شيء من هذا القبيل؟
Do I?
هل افعل؟
You are to spend the night with the Crown Prince.
عليك قضاء الليل مع ولي العهد.
What? You mean sleep with him?
ماذا؟ هل تقصد النوم معه؟
Yes.
نعم.
Wait, hold on. I am not physically ready...
انتظر، انتظر. أنا لست مستعدًا جسديًا...
I mean, I am not mentally prepared,
أعني أنني لست مستعدًا عقليًا،
and I just... Oh, I cannot.
وأنا فقط... أوه، لا أستطيع.
This is so mortifying.
هذا أمر مهين للغاية.
How are you feeling?
كيف تشعر؟
- Are you feeling okay? - Yes, well...
- هل تشعر أنك بخير؟ - نعم، حسنًا...
Yes, well...
نعم حسنا...
Well, yes.
حسنا، نعم.
Good.
جيد.
That is a relief.
هذا هو الراحة.
Hey, what are you doing with the tie?
مهلا، ماذا تفعل مع ربطة العنق؟
It is time for bed. It is late.
حان وقت النوم. الوقت متأخر.
What are you waiting for? Put out the light.
ماذا تنتظر؟ أطفئ النور.
Yes.
نعم.
I will turn it off.
سأقوم بإيقافه.
Gosh, this is not going to work.
يا إلهي، هذا لن ينجح.
Are you in pain?
هل تشعر بالألم؟
Your back?
ظهرك؟
No, I am fine. It is nothing.
لا، أنا بخير. لا شيء.
You are clearly not fine.
من الواضح أنك لست بخير.
Goodness.
الخير.
Here is some medicine.
وهنا بعض الدواء.
I will not look, so go on and apply it.
لن أنظر، لذا اذهب وطبقه.
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
- Do not look. - I am not looking.
- لا تنظر. - أنا لا أنظر.
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
Goodness.
الخير.
Are you done?
هل انتهيت؟
Hold on. It is on my back.
إنتظر، إنه على ظهري.
You see, applying something to one's own back,
كما ترى، فإن وضع شيء ما على ظهرك،
it is not easy, anatomically. One, two...
ليس الأمر سهلاً تشريحياً. واحد، اثنان...
This is so distracting.
هذا أمر مزعج للغاية.
Gosh, that hurts.
يا إلهي، هذا يؤلمني.
You said you would not look!
قلت أنك لن تنظر!
Calm down and hold still.
هدئ من روعك وحافظ على ثباتك.
Give me the ointment.
أعطني المرهم.
I am just treating your wound, so do not get any funny ideas.
أنا فقط أعالج جرحك، لذلك لا تفكر في أي أفكار مضحكة.
What? Who said I was?
ماذا؟ من قال أنني كذلك؟
The Queen Dowager.
الملكة الأرملة.
With a girl in this much pain,
مع وجود فتاة في هذا القدر من الألم،
what does she expect me to do?
ماذا تتوقع مني أن أفعل؟
It is not like I am an animal.
ليس الأمر وكأنني حيوان.
Turns out I am the animal here. It was me.
اتضح أنني الحيوان هنا. لقد كنت أنا.
What was that?
ماذا كان هذا؟
Nothing!
لا شئ!
I hate this. I really do.
أنا أكره هذا. أنا حقا أكرهه.
Did you hear the snake catcher family was recently wiped out?
هل سمعت أن عائلة صائد الثعابين تم القضاء عليها مؤخرًا؟
- They say it was the Jimjo Poison. - So I heard.
- يقولون أنها كانت سم جيمجو. - هذا ما سمعته.
It is terrifying. How is anyone supposed to live?
إنه أمر مرعب. كيف يُفترض أن يعيش أي شخص؟
I am telling you, a new Crown Princess is coming.
أنا أقول لك، أميرة ولي العهد الجديدة قادمة.
Queen Jangjeong's vengeful spirit is running rampant.
روح الانتقام للملكة جانججونج تنتشر بشكل كبير.
A woman determined to end the Royal Family's line...
امرأة عازمة على إنهاء سلالة العائلة المالكة...
- We were just getting some soup... - No.
- كنا نحصل فقط على بعض الحساء... - لا.
It is not a curse. It is the Jimjo Poison.
إنها ليست لعنة، بل هي سم جيمجو.
Good grief, were you not listening?
يا إلهي، هل لم تستمع؟
Curse or poison, it is a bad omen.
لعنة أو سم، فهو فأل سيئ.
Something so horrid to happen right before the Royal Wedding.
شيء فظيع للغاية حدث قبل الزفاف الملكي مباشرة.
Whose fault do you think it is? The new Crown Princess's, of course.
من المسؤول برأيك؟ بالطبع، ولي العهد الجديد.
For goodness' sake.
من أجل الخير.
Your Highness. Please do not mind such petty rumours.
صاحب السمو، أرجو ألا تُزعجك هذه الشائعات التافهة.
Let them gossip all they want. You will be the Crown Princess soon.
دعهم يثرثرون كما يشاؤون. ستصبحين أميرة التاج قريبًا.
The Chief Court Lady died recently, did she not?
لقد توفيت سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية مؤخرًا، أليس كذلك؟
Pardon?
عفو؟
Yes.
نعم.
But why bring up the Chief Court Lady all of a sudden?
ولكن لماذا إثارة موضوع سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية فجأة؟
No reason.
لا يوجد سبب.
I just thought maybe I would not become the Crown Princess...
لقد اعتقدت للتو أنني ربما لن أصبح ولي العهد ...
after all.
بعد كل شيء.
Are we...
هل نحن...
close enough to be holding hands?
هل هو قريب بما يكفي لكي نتمكن من الإمساك بالأيدي؟
This is a hand held in farewell.
هذه هي اليد التي تمسك بها في الوداع.
Please, call off this Royal Wedding.
من فضلكم، إلغاء هذا الزفاف الملكي.
This whole scenario feels awfully familiar.
يبدو هذا السيناريو بأكمله مألوفًا للغاية.
If I say no,
إذا قلت لا
are you going to shoot me again?
هل ستطلق النار علي مرة أخرى؟
It really hurt, by the way.
لقد كان الأمر مؤلمًا حقًا، بالمناسبة.
Getting shot.
تعرض لإطلاق النار.
If you knew everything, why did you not punish me?
إذا كنت تعرف كل شيء فلماذا لم تعاقبني؟
Because if you got hurt, Je Un would not be able to go on.
لأنه إذا تعرضت للأذى، لن يكون جي أون قادرًا على الاستمرار.
I am glad you are alive.
أنا سعيد لأنك على قيد الحياة.
What is this? A sudden change of heart?
ما هذا؟ تغيير مفاجئ في القلب؟
Because Prince Je Un needs at least one family member...
لأن الأمير جي أون يحتاج إلى عضو واحد على الأقل من العائلة...
like you, Your Royal Highness.
مثلك يا صاحب السمو الملكي.
I followed my ambitions, so I have no regrets.
لقد اتبعت طموحاتي، لذلك ليس لدي أي ندم.
And I intend to keep doing so.
وأنا أنوي الاستمرار في القيام بذلك.
I will give you the crucial evidence you need to bring down my father.
سأعطيك الدليل الحاسم الذي تحتاجه لإسقاط والدي.
Give me your word.
أعطني كلمتك.
If I tell you where the Jimjo is,
إذا أخبرتك أين يقع جيمجو،
you must guarantee that Prince Je Un and I...
يجب عليك ضمان أن الأمير جي أون وأنا ...
will be able to escape and live in safety.
سيكون قادرًا على الهروب والعيش بأمان.
Where is it?
أين هي؟
The Jimjo.
الجيمجو.
This Jimjo is how I seized control of Joseon.
هذا جيمجو هو كيف قمت بالسيطرة على جوسون.
But you know what?
ولكن هل تعلم ماذا؟
The Jimjo's true value...
القيمة الحقيقية لجيمجو...
is not in its poison, but in its secrecy.
ليس في سمّه، بل في سريته.
Once its existence is known, it is no better than any poison.
بمجرد معرفة وجوده، فهو ليس أفضل من أي سم.
But now, rumours of the Jimjo Poison are spreading among the people.
لكن الآن، تنتشر شائعات حول سم جيمجو بين الناس.
Did you use the Jimjo Poison on the snake catchers?
هل استخدمت السم جيمجو على صائد الثعابين؟
Now that I have been exposed,
الآن بعد أن تعرضت للخطر،
I feared a Police Bureau inquiry would lead to the guild,
كنت خائفًا من أن يؤدي تحقيق مكتب الشرطة إلى النقابة،
so I made their deaths mysterious...
لذلك جعلت موتهم غامضًا...
The Jimjo Poison...
السم جيمجو...
should have only been used for the Gyesa Year Incident.
كان ينبغي أن يتم استخدامه فقط لحادثة عام جيسا.
The Gyesa Year Incident was meant to remain a rumour forever.
كان من المفترض أن تظل حادثة عام جيسا مجرد شائعة إلى الأبد.
But you have ruined everything.
ولكنك دمرت كل شيء.
Please kill me.
من فضلك اقتلني.
I will be the one to decide when you die.
أنا سوف أكون الشخص الذي يقرر متى تموت.
Seal off every secret passage connected to this place.
أغلق كل الممرات السرية المتصلة بهذا المكان.
And if the Crown Prince manages to find his way here,
وإذا تمكن ولي العهد من الوصول إلى هنا،
eliminate him.
القضاء عليه.
The Crown Prince...
ولي العهد...
You are ordering me to kill him?
أنت تأمرني بقتله؟
It is a beautiful day, is it not?
إنه يوم جميل، أليس كذلك؟
- Yes. - Heard of the new royal concubine?
- نعم. - هل سمعت عن المحظية الملكية الجديدة؟
So what if she got the title?
فماذا لو حصلت على اللقب؟
I heard His Royal Highness has only visited her once.
سمعت أن صاحب السمو الملكي زارها مرة واحدة فقط.
Still, I am jealous she gets to be a royal concubine.
مع ذلك، أنا أشعر بالغيرة لأنها أصبحت محظية ملكية.
Jealous? She is just a replacement.
غيورة؟ هي مجرد بديل.
Exactly. To replace the last one.
بالضبط. ليحل محل الأخير.
The nerve of those girls.
جرأة هؤلاء الفتيات.
Just ignore them.
فقط تجاهلهم .
You see a chicken a lot more often than a pheasant, right?
أنت ترى الدجاج أكثر بكثير من طائر الدراج، أليس كذلك؟
My lady, why are you out here? You should be inside.
سيدتي، لماذا أنتِ هنا؟ يجب أن تكوني في الداخل.
There is a distillery at the foot of Mount Inwang.
هناك مصنع تقطير عند سفح جبل إنوانج.
It belonged to my father for a long time,
لقد كانت ملكًا لوالدي لفترة طويلة،
but one day, he gave ownership to the former Chief Court Lady.
ولكن في يوم من الأيام، أعطى الملكية إلى سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية السابقة.
And shortly after that,
وبعد ذلك بفترة وجيزة،
the Gyesa Year Incident took place.
وقعت حادثة عام جيسا.
(The distillery)
(المقطرة)
The distillery.
المقطرة.
This way.
من هنا.
This is a regular cave, is it not? If it is not here,
هذا كهف عادي، أليس كذلك؟ إن لم يكن هنا،
how could a Jimjo possibly live in that tiny house?
كيف يمكن لجيمجو أن يعيش في هذا المنزل الصغير؟
There is something to this distillery. Otherwise,
هناك شيء مميز في هذه المقطرة. وإلا،
the Chief Court Lady's deed and this secret passage...
وثيقة سيدة المحكمة الرئيسية والممر السري هذا...
would not make any sense.
لن يكون هناك أي معنى.
And how do you explain the fledgling's frantic cries?
وكيف تفسر صرخات الفرخ المحمومة؟
- A rat! - Will you keep it down?
- فأر! - هل ستبقيه في الأسفل؟
Do you hear that?
هل تسمع ذلك؟
The sound of chains.
صوت السلاسل.
There is definitely something in here.
هناك بالتأكيد شيئا هنا.
- The sound is getting louder. - I know.
- الصوت أصبح أعلى. - أعلم.
Darn it.
لعنة عليك.
Why did you bring that?
لماذا احضرت ذلك؟
We are facing the monster Jimjo. Was I supposed to come empty-handed?
نحن نواجه الوحش جيمجو. هل كان من المفترض أن آتي خالي الوفاض؟
Darn.
الرتق.
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
(Yeon Wol, I will avenge you)
(يون وول، سأنتقم لك)
This one thing...
هذا الشيء الواحد...
is mine.
هي ملكي.
What about Dal?
ماذا عن دال؟
Where is Dal?
أين دال؟
I thought she said she would wait. Did she leave already?
ظننتُ أنها قالت إنها ستنتظر. هل غادرت بالفعل؟
- Did she go to the Jimjo chick? - What?
- هل ذهبت إلى فتاة جيمجو؟ - ماذا؟
Why would Dal go there?
لماذا يذهب دال إلى هناك؟
- Right. It was a secret. - Spit it out!
- صحيح. كان سرًا. - اكشفه!
The thing is...
الشئ هو...
Lady Park wanted to help with the Gyesa Year Incident.
أرادت السيدة بارك المساعدة في حادثة عام جيسا.
So she guards the chick every day from the Left State Councillor.
لذلك فهي تحرس الفرخ كل يوم من مستشار الدولة اليساري.
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
- Hey. - Yes?
- مهلا. - نعم؟
What were you thinking?
ماذا كنت تفكر؟
How could you let Dal come here all by herself?
كيف يمكنك السماح لدال أن تأتي إلى هنا بمفردها؟
What if the Left State Councillor had actually sent his men after her?
ماذا لو كان المستشار اليساري للدولة قد أرسل رجاله في الواقع وراءها؟
No, of course I tried to stop her.
لا، بالطبع حاولت إيقافها.
Wait, but...
انتظر ولكن...
If she did not come here,
لو لم تأت إلى هنا،
then why did she just leave?
إذن لماذا رحلت للتو؟
Why did you put ointment on my wounds?
لماذا وضعت مرهماً على جروحي؟
I hope it would hurt a little less.
آمل أن يكون الألم أقل قليلا.
Why did you shield me?
لماذا حميتني؟
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
I will be your shield,
سأكون درعك
and you will hide behind me.
وسوف تختبئ خلفي.
And yet, all you have left for me is a sense of duty.
ومع ذلك، كل ما تبقى لي هو الشعور بالواجب.
This concubine appointment is a matter of responsibility.
إن تعيين هذه المحظية هو مسألة مسؤولية.
She is the one who saved my life and was harmed because of me.
إنها هي التي أنقذت حياتي وتضررت بسببي.
How could I possibly turn my back on her?
كيف يمكنني أن أدير ظهري لها؟
Is this feeling a sickness too?
هل هذا الشعور مرض أيضاً؟
The more I fall for him,
كلما وقعت في حبه أكثر،
the more of a coward I become.
كلما أصبحت أكثر جبانًا.
How pathetic.
كم هو مثير للشفقة.
What? You might as well just faint.
ماذا؟ من الأفضل أن تغمى عليك.
If I passed out, you would just leave me behind.
إذا فقدت الوعي، فسوف تتركني خلفك.
I am tempted to leave you behind even if you do not.
أشعر بالرغبة في تركك خلفي حتى لو لم تفعل ذلك.
You will guard this place every day so Dal is never left alone here.
سوف تقوم بحراسة هذا المكان كل يوم حتى لا يترك دال وحيدًا هنا أبدًا.
- Got it? - You want me to...
- فهمت؟ - تريد مني أن...
guard this place? This place that is crawling with rats? Me?
أحرس هذا المكان؟ هذا المكان المليء بالجرذان؟ أنا؟
To the rats, you are the scary one, you idiot.
بالنسبة للفئران، أنت الشخص المخيف، أيها الأحمق.
That is why they are all scurrying away from you.
ولهذا السبب فإنهم جميعًا يبتعدون عنك.
Rats?
جرذان؟
Rats!
الجرذان!
Rats.
الفئران.
It was not a wall.
لم يكن جدارا.
It was a door all along.
لقد كان بابًا طوال الوقت.
Come out.
يخرج.
Who is there?
من هناك؟
It is the Choraengi Mask.
إنه قناع تشوراينجي.
Destroy this place,
دمر هذا المكان
and make the Crown Prince himself release the Jimjo.
وجعل ولي العهد بنفسه يطلق سراح الجيمجو.
Seize him!
إمسكوه!
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
It is explosive!
إنه متفجر!
Yoon Se Dol!
يون سي دول!
Get out!
اخرج!
It's the Jimjo! Go after it!
إنه جيمجو! اذهب خلفه!
Yes, Your Highness!
نعم يا صاحب السمو!
- Go after it! - Yes, Your Highness!
- اذهب وراءه! - نعم، سموكم!
That is toward the palace.
وهذا باتجاه القصر.
Its maternal instinct is strong. It must be going to its chick.
غريزتها الأمومية قوية. لا بد أنها ذاهبة إلى فرخها.
We have to get to the palace immediately.
علينا أن نصل إلى القصر فورًا.
Lady Park wanted to help with the Gyesa Year Incident.
أرادت السيدة بارك المساعدة في حادثة عام جيسا.
So she guards the chick every day from the Left State Councillor.
لذلك فهي تحرس الفرخ كل يوم من مستشار الدولة اليساري.
Dal.
من.
The Jimjo's tracks...
مسارات جيمجو...
are all gone.
لقد رحلوا جميعا.
There is no other way now.
لا يوجد طريقة أخرى الآن.
We must capture the Jimjo alive.
يجب علينا القبض على جيمجو حيًا.
What is that?
ما هذا؟
Look! Over there! What is that?
انظروا! هناك! ما هذا؟
- What is all this commotion? - Your Majesty, look over there...
- ما كل هذه الضجة؟ - جلالتك، انظر هناك...
My goodness, what in the world is that?
يا إلهي، ما هذا في العالم؟
I am not sure, Your Majesty.
أنا لست متأكدًا، جلالتك.
A Jimjo?
وجيمجو؟
Your Majesty, it is dangerous! Please get to safety.
يا جلالة الملك، الوضع خطير! يرجى توخي الحذر.
- Your Majesty. Hurry! - Yes. Get Her Majesty to safety.
- جلالتك. أسرع! - نعم. أوصل جلالتها إلى بر الأمان.
- Yes! - This way.
- نعم! - من هنا.
Why is the Jimjo here?
لماذا جيمجو هنا؟
The chick?
الفرخة؟
- Get the flaming arrows ready! - Yes, sir!
- جهزوا السهام المشتعلة! - نعم سيدي!
Once I capture the Jimjo alive...
بمجرد أن أتمكن من القبض على جيمجو حيًا...
and prove its habitat is linked to the Left State Councillor,
وإثبات أن موطنه مرتبط بمستشار الدولة اليساري،
he will be finished for treason.
سيتم القضاء عليه بتهمة الخيانة.
I have staked my life on this revenge.
لقد راهنت بحياتي على هذا الانتقام.
If it dies here,
إذا مات هنا،
we cannot prove the Left State Councillor is behind this.
لا يمكننا أن نثبت أن المستشار اليساري للدولة هو الذي يقف وراء هذا.
We have to capture it alive. I cannot let that happen.
علينا أن نلتقطه حيًا. لا أستطيع السماح بحدوث ذلك.
We must capture it alive.
يجب علينا أن نلتقطه حيًا.
Lady Park, you should not get involved. Please get to safety.
ليدي بارك، لا تتدخلي. رجاءً، احرصي على سلامتكِ.
I will take full responsibility.
سأتحمل المسؤولية كاملة.
I will lure the bird. Evacuate the court ladies first.
سأغري الطائر. أخلِوا البلاطَ يا سيداتِ أولاً.
Then, have the Royal Guard go to the square and prepare the ropes.
ثم اطلب من الحرس الملكي أن يذهب إلى الساحة ويقوم بإعداد الحبال.
It must be captured alive.
ينبغي أن يتم القبض عليه حياً.
- Go. - Yes, my lady.
- اذهب. - نعم سيدتي.
What are you waiting for? Hurry!
ماذا تنتظر؟ أسرع!
Yes, we will move to Injeongjeon Hall.
نعم، سوف ننتقل إلى قاعة إنجيونججيون.
- To the Injeongjeon Hall! - Yes, sir!
- إلى قاعة إنجونغجيون! - نعم سيدي!
Your Royal Highness, Lady Park...
صاحبة السمو الملكي، السيدة بارك...
Dal, do not do anything.
دال، لا تفعل شيئا.
Please, do not do anything reckless.
من فضلك لا تفعل أي شيء متهور.
I am sorry.
أنا آسف.
It is here!
إنه هنا!
Your chick is right here!
فرخك موجود هنا!
Gosh!
يا إلهي!
Lady Park, get back!
ليدي بارك، عودي!
Take it! Do not let it escape!
خذها! لا تدعها تهرب!
- Do not let it escape! - Yes, sir!
- لا تدعه يهرب! - نعم سيدي!
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
I am alive.
انا على قيد الحياة.
What, you think you have nine lives? That death will just spare you?
ماذا، أتظن أن لديك تسع أرواح؟ هذا الموت سينقذك؟
What in the world were you thinking?
ماذا كنت تفكر في العالم؟
But I...
ولكن انا...
I was just...
لقد كنت فقط...
trying to help you.
أحاول مساعدتك.
I told you not to help! I told you repeatedly to stay out.
قلت لك لا تساعد! قلت لك مراراً وتكراراً أن تبقى خارجاً.
Why do you keep interfering with my revenge?
لماذا تستمر في التدخل في انتقامي؟
You nearly ruined everything!
لقد دمرت كل شيء تقريبًا!
It is because I know how much this revenge means to you.
لأنني أعلم مدى أهمية هذا الانتقام بالنسبة لك.
How could I just stand by and do nothing?
كيف يمكنني أن أقف مكتوف الأيدي ولا أفعل شيئًا؟
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي.
Jimjo poison.
سم جيمجو.
It has a clear, odourless, tasteless oil.
إنه يحتوي على زيت شفاف، عديم الرائحة والطعم.
From the oil gland in its wattle.
من الغدة الزيتية الموجودة في لحمها.
If it dies...
إذا مات...
It is all over.
لقد انتهى كل شيء.
Everything...
كل شئ...
is over.
لقد انتهى.
Because of me.
بسببي.
It is all ruined because of me.
لقد دمر كل شيء بسببي.
Gang Yeon Wol.
جانج يون وول.
You are like the heavens,
أنت مثل السماوات
and your heart...
وقلبك...
I will hold it forever, with no regrets.
سأحتفظ بها إلى الأبد، دون أي ندم.
You must...
يجب عليك أن...
fly free...
تطير بحرية...
and rest in peace.
و ارقدي بسلام.
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
Why are you sleeping out here?
لماذا تنام هنا؟
No reason.
لا يوجد سبب.
I just could not bring myself...
لم أستطع أن أحمل نفسي...
to sleep soundly.
النوم بعمق.
I am so sorry.
أنا آسف جدًا.
I have ruined everything.
لقد دمرت كل شيء.
The most important thing to you, Your Highness,
أهم شيء بالنسبة لك، صاحب السمو،
was avenging the Crown Princess.
كان ينتقم لولي العهد.
And now, because of me, it is all ruined.
والآن، بسببي، كل شيء دمر.
What are you talking about?
ماذا تتحدث عنه؟
I protected what was most important.
لقد قمت بحماية ما هو الأكثر أهمية.
But the Jimjo is dead, so your revenge is ruined, is it not?
لكن جيمجو مات، لذا فإن انتقامك قد دمر، أليس كذلك؟
For that revenge...
من أجل الانتقام...
I heard you were even willing to risk your life.
سمعت أنك كنت على استعداد للمخاطرة بحياتك.
Revenge was the only way...
كان الانتقام هو السبيل الوحيد...
I could atone to the Crown Princess.
أستطيع التكفير عن ذنب ولي العهد.
Filled with so much hatred and guilt,
مليئة بالكثير من الكراهية والذنب،
I could not come to you.
لم أستطع المجيء إليك.
But if you had died,
ولكن لو مت،
I would have had nowhere left to go.
لم يكن لدي مكان آخر أذهب إليه.
I just...
انا فقط...
I thought...
اعتقدت...
you must be furious with me.
لا بد أنك غاضب مني.
So furious you would never want to see me again.
أنا غاضب جدًا لدرجة أنك لن ترغب في رؤيتي مرة أخرى.
I thought that all day, so I just...
لقد اعتقدت ذلك طوال اليوم، لذلك أنا فقط...
The fault is not yours. It is mine.
الخطأ ليس خطؤك، بل خطئي.
I was angry at myself for always...
لقد كنت غاضبًا من نفسي دائمًا...
putting you in harm's way.
وضعك في طريق الأذى.
How could I ever be angry with you?
كيف يمكنني أن أغضب منك؟
You are the sole exception to all my anger.
أنت الاستثناء الوحيد لكل غضبي.
I meant to tell you after my revenge was complete.
أردت أن أخبرك بعد أن أنتهي من انتقامي.
But you are having such foolish thoughts,
ولكن لديك مثل هذه الأفكار الحمقاء،
so I have no choice but to tell you now.
لذلك ليس لدي خيار سوى أن أخبرك الآن.
That I...
أنني...
I am very deeply...
أنا عميق جدًا...
in love...
يعشق...
with you, Park Dal.
معك بارك دال.
Me too.
أنا أيضاً.
(Moon River)
(نهر القمر)
I am not going to let you go, even if you talk my ear off.
لن أسمح لك بالرحيل، حتى لو تحدثت معي طويلاً.
So you hold on to me tight too.
لذلك أنت تتمسك بي بقوة أيضًا.
The Crown Prince and his Concubine are so lovey-dovey.
ولي العهد وخليلته يحبون بعضهما البعض كثيرًا.
The entire palace is buzzing. And if she were to conceive...
القصر كله يعجّ بالحيوية. ولو حملت...
Who do I look like to you now?
من أبدو لك الآن؟
And I... who do you see before you now?
وأنا... من ترى أمامك الآن؟
Because of one woman,
بسبب امرأة واحدة،
five years of hard work have crumbled to dust.
خمس سنوات من العمل الشاق تحولت إلى غبار.
A fledgling Jimjo's toxin is weak.
سموم جيمجو الصغيرة ضعيفة.
It cannot become a true Jimjo.
لا يمكن أن يصبح جيمجو حقيقيًا.
It seems another sacrifice will be required.
يبدو أن هناك حاجة إلى تضحيات أخرى.
(Moon River)
(نهر القمر)